Register of the Henry Mauris Robinson Papers, 1917-1936
Hoover Institution Archives
Henry Mauris Robinson Papers,
1917-1936
43001
Robinson, Henry Mauris, 1868-1937
34 manuscript boxes, 1 envelope (13.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, speeches and writings, reports, minutes of meetings, memoranda, conference documents, notes, and printed matter, relating to the United States Council of National Defense during World War I, the Paris Peace Conference, the Allied Supreme Economic Council, the Dawes and Young Committees on Reparations, and the International Economic Conference of 1927
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1943.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Allied and Associated Powers (1914-1920) Supreme Economic Council; Inter-Allied Commission for Reparations; United States. Council of National Defense; International Economic Conference (1927: Geneva); Paris Peace Conference (1919-1920); International economic relations; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1914-1918--Peace; World War, 1914-1918--Reparations; World War, 1914-1918--United States; United States--Politics and government; United States--Foreign relations; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964
Biographical Note
1868, September 12 born, Ravenna, Ohio
1886-1888 student, Cornell University
1917-1918 staff, Council of National Defense
1919 member, Supreme Economic Council, Paris Peace Conference
1919 commissioner, U.S. Shipping Board
1919 representative of U.S., First International Labor Conference
1919 member, President's 2nd Industrial Conference
1920 Chairman, Bituminous Coal Commission
1924 member 2nd Committee of Experts on Reparations
1927 chairman, American Delegation to International Economic Conference
1929 member, Young Committee on Reparations
1929 member, President's Economic Stabilization Conference
1929-1930 member, Executive Committee, National Business Survey Conference, U.S. Chamber of Commerce
Series Description
- Correspondence, 1917-1924. (Box 1-4)
  Correspondence, arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
- Subject File, 1917-1932. (Box 5-26)
  Correspondence, memoranda, reports, minutes of meetings, lists, charts, notes, printed matter, and clippings, arranged alphabetically by subject.
- Increment (Box 27.)
  Letters sent by Henry M. Robinson as well as letters, telegrams, and memoranda received from Rufus Dawes, Leon Fresor, Owen D. Young, Herbert Hoover, Fred Bate, and others, relating to reparations.
Container List
- Correspondence, 1917-1924
  - A (Box 1)
  - Allen, Frederick L.
  - B
  - Baker, Newton W.
  - Bamberger, J.E.
  - Barber, John E.
  - Baruch, Bernard
  - Beaton, G.A.
  - Benson, Admiral W.S.
  - Blackman, William
  - Bloomfield, Meyer
  - Buehl, C.L.
  - C
  - Clarkson, Grosvenor
  - Clementel, M. Paris
  - Collins, James H. (Box 2)
  - Constantine, Arthur
  - Cowen, C.P.
  - Cravens, John S.
  - D
  - Davis, Norman H.
  - Douglas, J.S.
  - Dulles, John Foster
  - E
  - F
  - Fleming, Arthur H.
  - Flint, Frank P.
  - Forbes, Allan B.
  - G
  - Gompers, Samuel
  - Graham, S.C.
  - Grew, J.C.
  - H
  - Haight, Charles S.
  - Halinbourg, F.
  - Hoover, Herbert (Box 3)
  - Howard, Roy W.
  - Hurley, Edward N.
  - Hyman, David M.
  - J
  - K
  - L
  - Lansing, Robert
  - Lord, Frank B.
  - M
  - McAdoo, William G.
  - Moore, John Bassett
  - N
  - O
  - P
  - Payne, John B.
  - R (Box 4)
  - Reynolds, D.M.
  - Robinson, L.A.
  - Robinson, R.H.M.
  - S
  - Scott, Thomas A.
  - Shoup, Paul
  - Smuggler Leasing Company
  - Stayton, William H.
  - Suzzallo, Henry
  - T
  - Thane, A.F.
  - W
  - Ward, William C.
  - Wilson, Woodrow
- Subject File, 1917-1932
  - Agriculture, Co-operative Marketing (Box 5)
  - Bessemer Process for Steel Production in Europe
  - Biographical Sketch
  - Bituminous Coal Commission, 1920
  - Council of National Defense, 1917-1918
    - Correspondence
      - General
      - Arizona
      - Arkansas
      - California
      - Idaho
      - Mississippi
      - Nevada
      - New Mexico
      - Oregon
      - Utah (Box 6)
      - Washington (State)
      - Wisconsin
      - Wyoming
    - Minutes of Governing Board
    - Minutes of Staff Meetings
    - Memoranda and Reports
    - Weekly Reports of Activities by State Councils
    - Weekly Supplements to Reports
    - Organization Chart
    - Partial List of Bulletins, Information Circulars, and General Letters by Subject
    - Bulletins
    - Bulletins (Box 7)
    - Information Circulars
    - General Letters, No. 6-163
    - Subject File (Box 8)
      - American Defense Society
      - Americanization of Aliens
      - Housing for Labor
      - Labor
      - Shipbuilding Industry
      - War Savings Campaign
    - Letters of Introduction
    - Mailing List
    - Speech, July 3, (1917)
    - Posters
    - Editorials
    - Miscellaneous Printed Matter
  - Dawes Committee on Reparations, 1924
    - Correspondence, December, 1923 - October 1924
    - Agenda and Assignments
    - List of Members and Organization Chart
    - Minutes of Meetings, First Committee of Experts
    - Minutes of Meetings, Second Committee of Experts (Box 9)
    - London Conference Final Protocol, August 16, 1924
    - Report of the First Committee of Experts to the Reparations Commission
    - Report of the Second Committee of Experts to the Reparations Commission
    - General Report on German Railways
    - Report of Technical Experts on Consumption Taxes
    - Budget Memoranda
    - Memoranda of Technical Experts (Box 10)
    - Questionaires on Flight of Capital
    - Questionaires
    - Plans, Drafts, and Corrections for Final Reports
    - Preliminary Reports
    - Information Collected by the First Committee of Experts on German Railways
    - Information Collected by the First Committee of Experts on the German Budget
    - Information Collected by the Second Committee of Experts on Flight of Capital (Box 11)
    - Subject File of Memoranda
      - Agriculture
      - Army Costs
      - Austrian Reconstruction
      - Balance of Trade and Payments
      - Bank and Currency Plans (Box 12)
      - Banking Conditions
      - Belgian Debt
      - British Position
      - Deliveries in Kind
      - Exchange and Exchange Control
      - Flight of Capital from Germany
      - French Position
      - General Economic Conditions in Germany
      - German Budget
      - German Debt (Box 13)
      - German Exploitation of Occupied Territory
      - German Foreign Assets
      - German Mortgages
      - German Public Works
      - German Railway Company
      - German Railways
      - Implementation of Dawes Plan
      - Interallied Debts
      - Italian Position
      - Joseph Stamp Proposal
      - Loans and Financing
      - Measurement of Prosperity
      - M.I.C.U.M. (Interallied Mission of Control of Factories and Mines) Agreements
      - Monopolies and Consumption Taxes
    - Subject File of Memoranda (Box 14)
      - Prices
      - Rentenbank and Reichsbank
      - Reparation Plans
      - Summary of Reparations Problem
      - Taxation
      - The Ruhr
      - Transferability of German Payments
      - Treaty of Versailles
      - U.S. Position
      - Miscellaneous
    - Reparation Commission Official Communiques
    - Reparation Commission Memoranda
    - Reparation Commission Minutes (Box 15)
    - Reparation Commission Annexes
    - Committee on Guarantees Intelligence Service Reports (Berlin), nos. 698-2632 (incomplete)
    - Committee on Guarantees Intelligence Service Reports (Berlin), nos. 2637-3050 (incomplete) (Box 16)
    - Committee on Guarantees Intelligence Service Reports (Berlin), nos. 3066-3243 (incomplete) (Box 17)
    - Committee on Guarantees Intelligence Service Reports (Paris), nos. 475-3308 (incomplete)
    - Committee on Guarantees Intelligence Service Weekly Summaries
    - Committee on Guarantees Annexes (Box 18)
    - Committee on Guarantees Index of Minutes
    - List of Dawes Committee Records
    - Document Check-our Slips
    - Notes
    - Belgian Press Coverage
    - French Press Coverage
    - German Press Coverage (Box 19)
    - Clippings
    - Memorabilia
  - Hoover, Herbert, Speech by H.M. Robinson, A Non-solipsistic Stay in the White House
  - Income Tax, Personal
  - International Chamber of Commerce
  - International Economic Conference, 1927
    - Correspondence
    - Conference Report
    - Commerce Commission Reports
    - Co-ordination Commission Reports
    - Industrial Commission Reports
    - Preparatory Committee Reports and Minutes
    - U.S. Position Papers and Statements (Box 20)
    - Documents Submitted to the Conference
    - Miscellaneous Conference Documents
    - List of Delegates
    - Printed Matter
    - Clippings
  - International Labor Conference of the League of Nations, 1919 (Box 21)
  - Miscellany
  - Morson School of Practical Economics
  - National Conference on Public Spending and Private Business, 1927
  - National Industrial Conference, 1919
  - Navy League of the U.S.
  - Newspaper Clippings, Miscellaneous
  - Paris Peace Conference, 1919
    - Miscellaneous
    - Commission on International Labor Legislation (Box 22)
      - Correspondence, March - May 1919
      - Final Report to Peace Conference
      - Official Minutes of Proceedings
      - Convention Creating Permanent Organization
      - Official Communiques
      - Draft Proposals
      - Notes on Meetings of Commission
      - U.S. Position Statements
      - Delegate's Pass and Form Letters
      - Clippings
    - Commission on Reparations of Damages, 1919
      - Reports
      - Minutes of Meetings
      - Memoranda and Draft Proposals (Box 23)
      - Notes
  - Reparations and War Debt, 1929-1932
  - Supreme Economic Council, 1919
    - Organization Chart and Miscellaneous Documents
    - Documents of Special Meetings
    - Documents of Meetings 1-10, February 17 - March 24 (Meeting 6, missing)
    - Documents of Meetings 11-13, April 7 - April 22 (Box 24)
    - Documents of Meetings 15-20, April 28 - May 28
  - Turkey
  - U.S. Shipping Board, 1919 (Box 25)
  - Young Committee on Reparations, 1929
    - List of Notes of Economic Service
    - Notes of Economic Service, nos. 1-29
    - Notes of Economic Service, nos. 30-67 (Box 26)
    - List of Documents of Economic Service
    - Documents of Economic Service
    - Reparation Commission Annexes, 1925
- Increment
  - Letters sent by Henry M. Robinson as well as letters, telegrams, and memoranda received from Rufus Dawes, Leon Fresor, Owen D. Young, Herbert Hoover, Fred Bate, and others, relating to reparations. (Box 27)